iea.org 2019-11-28

# Privacy protection

Home » Terms and Conditions, Use and Copyright  » Privacy protection

## Privacy Policy

* * *

 **Privacy Policy**

_Updated and effective from 12 April 2018_

The International Energy Agency of 31-35 rue de la Fédération, 75015 Paris, France ( **IEA** ), an autonomous agency within the framework of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development ( **OECD** ), is committed to the protection of personal information.

This Privacy Policy explains what information the IEA may collect from you and how we may manage and use that information. We undertake to ensure that any personal information you provide is collected and used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**1.  ** **General**

The personal information that you submit to the IEA, for the purposes specified when you submitted such information, will be managed in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

By using the IEA websites and/or registering your details for a purchase or for acquiring other information, you agree to the processing of your personal information for such purposes and as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Registration on the IEA websites is optional. You can use www.iea.org and the IEA web store when you choose not to provide personal information. However, certain features of the website and webstore that require registration may be unavailable (for example, downloads, online purchases or e-mail alerts).

**2.  ** **Collection of personal information**   

_Information the IEA **collects automatically** on the IEA websites_

If you visit the IEA websites to read or download information, we automatically recognise, collect and store the following information: the date and time of your visit, the originating internet protocol ( **IP** ) address, the type of browser and operating system (if provided by the browser), the URL of the referring page (if provided by the browser), the object requested, the completion status of the request, and, in some cases, the username and password.

_Personal information you **register** on the IEA websites_

When purchasing or before downloading products from the IEA webstore, you are required to register. You are asked to provide the following personal information: first and last name, email address, company name, password and sector of activity.

At checkout you are requested to provide a billing address, shipping address and payment information. However, your payment information is collected and processed solely by Société Générale and is not collected, stored nor processed in any manner by the IEA.

You can also confirm that you want us to use your email address in order to send you email updates as set out below under section 3.

Subscribers to the Online Data Service and Oil Market Report are asked to provide name, postal address, e-mail address and telephone number. 

**Please note that the IEA will never ask you for passwords, credit card details or financial data through unsolicited emails or calls.**

_General_

The IEA may ask you to provide personal information in other contexts, for example, in connection with your participation in IEA events such as workshops and conferences, other IEA activities or for surveys. The IEA will explain the specific purpose for which it requests your consent to collect and use your personal information, and the extent to which it will process your personal information for such purpose(s).  If you give your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time (see below).

**3.  ** **Use of collected personal information**

_Information the IEA collects automatically on the IEA websites_

We use information that we have obtained automatically from the IEA websites in ways necessary to successfully provide, operate, maintain and optimise our website (which we also believe benefit our website visitors) including to enable smooth website traffic, for technical support (debugging any problems that arise) and to manage and enhance our website security.

_Personal information you register on the IEA websites and IEA webstore_

The personal information that you register on the IEA websites, including the IEA webstore, is necessary to fulfil our contract with you when you purchase or subscribe to IEA material.  For example, we use it to process and complete your purchase of, or subscription to, the products that you requested, to maintain communication with you with respect to the status of your order, to send you the relevant items purchased or subscribed to and the related invoices and receipts, and to respond to any queries that you might have about the transaction.

We also use personal information that you have registered on the IEA websites and IEA webstore for the following customer service purposes:

  * To allow you to obtain IEA products in a straightforward way and to provide you with personalised service, including so you won’t need to re-enter all of your details if you are a returning customer;
  * To allow the IEA to analyze your profile so as to personalise or otherwise improve our offering to you;
  * To send you e-mails confirming and managing your account such as to send you temporary passwords should you request one, perform updates on your information or notify you of data breaches;
  * To contact you for feedback (including via surveys) so that we may improve or develop our products, services or content; and
  * To respond to your email queries.

Where you have given your express consent, we and/or our third party service providers will also use the information to provide you with relevant IEA email newsletters, notifications, updates.

_General_

Personal information you submitted to the IEA in other contexts will only be used for the specific and legitimate purpose(s) for which it was collected and as explained to you at the time of collection.

**4.  ** **Management and security of collected personal information**

The IEA endeavours to collect and manage personal information in a responsible way, taking the necessary and appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect and safeguard your information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. These measures are reviewed and updated where necessary.

Collected personal information will be used for the abovementioned purposes only and will not be further processed or distributed in a manner that is incompatible with this Privacy Policy.

The number of staff that have access to and process personal information for the relevant purpose(s) is limited to the strict minimum.  These staff are obligated to respect the privacy and confidentiality of such personal information.

**5.  ** **Length of time we use and store your personal information**

_Information the IEA collects automatically on the IEA websites_

The automatically collected information on IEA websites is retained for a maximum period of two years but usually no more than 6 months.

_Personal information you register on the IEA websites_

The personal information you register on the IEA webstore is retained for a maximum period of three years, starting from the moment you register. This period is renewed for another three years anytime a purchase or download is made using the same registered user account. However, personal data of subscription users are kept until three years after the subscription expires.

_General_

Personal information collected in other contexts by the IEA will be kept only as long as required for the specified purpose at the time of collection.

**6.   ** **Disclosure** **of information**

We are committed to keeping your personal information confidential. The IEA will not disclose your personal information to third parties unless required to perform the abovementioned purposes e.g. secure external payment server, third party email dispatch services, survey providers.  They will process your data on our behalf and solely in accordance with our instructions.  We will retain control over and remain fully responsible for your personal data and will use appropriate safeguards to ensure the integrity and security of your personal data when engaging such service providers.

**7.   ** **Information about international transfers**

Your personal information may be stored and processed on our behalf in countries other than your country of residence where we engage third party service providers to assist us to perform the abovementioned purposes.  You acknowledge and agree that your personal information may be transferred to countries outside of your country of residence which may have different data protection rules.  We will ensure that where third party service providers have access to personal information outside of the EEA, appropriate protections are in place.

**8.   ** **Third parties and links**

Throughout the IEA websites, you may find links to other third-party websites. Please note that the IEA is not responsible for any aspects of such third-party websites or for the information they collect from or about you or your actions e.g. if you use a social media sharing button the social network that has created the button may record that you shared a post.

IEA websites may also include links to third-party web servers for online payments, which may have different privacy policies. You are therefore encouraged to review their privacy policies, when visiting these websites.

**9.   ** **Sensitive data**

The IEA does not knowingly solicit or collect, and you should not provide to the IEA, any information regarding your medical or health condition, race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetics, biometrics or other sensitive data.

**10.   ** **Children**

The IEA websites are not directed at children under the age of 13.  We do not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

**11.   ****Accessing, updating and removing your personal information**

We wish to ensure that the personal information that we retain in our databases is up to date and accurate. The IEA undertakes reasonable steps to rectify inaccurate personal information without delay, having regard to the purposes for which it is processed.

If you want to access, amend or correct your personal information, you may do so at any time through your registration settings or by e-mailing us at [webstore@iea.org](mailto:webstore@iea.org).

Any requests for restriction of processing, deletion of personal information, or queries on whether the IEA holds personal information on you, can also be forwarded to [webstore@iea.org](mailto:webstore@iea.org) or to the physical address mentioned in section 13 below.You can obtain on request a readable print-out of your personal data held by the IEA at reasonable intervals and without charge.

Before granting any request in this regard, we may ask you to provide proof of your identity.  If you are not able to provide proof of your identity, we reserve the right to refuse changes or deletion of the personal information in question.

If you consented to receive email updates and newsletters from us, we will provide you with the ability to opt out of receiving such material from us at any time.

**12.   ****Notification of Changes**

We will advise you of any material amendments to this Privacy Policy by placing a notice on the IEA website. Please check the ‘updated and effective from’ date at the beginning of this Privacy Policy to find out when it came into effect.  We reserve the right to make amendments to the Privacy Policy as needed.

**13.   ****Privacy Support and Complaint**

If you have any questions, comments or complaints about our Privacy Policy please e-mail us at [webstore@iea.org](mailto:webstore@iea.org) or write to us at International Energy Agency, IEA webstore, 31-35 rue de la Fédération, 75015, Paris, France.
